Guide to the Charles S. Sydnor Papers, 1729-1978and undated RL.01273
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Charles S. Sydnor papers
1729-1978 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sydnor, Charles S. (Charles Sackett), 1898-1954.
RL.01273
14.8 Linear Feet
circa 11,159 items
Access Restriction
Part of the Teaching Files Series in this collection is restricted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Charles S. Sydnor Papers (1729-1978 and undated) were donated to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1990 by members of the Sydnor family.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1898, July 21 Born, Augusta, Ga.
1915 Graduated from Darlington School, Rome, Ga.
1918 B.A., Hampden-Sydney College, Hampden-Sydney, Va.
1919 Taught high school in Rome, Ga.
1919-1920 Taught at McCallie School, Chattanooga, Tenn.
1923 Ph.D., Johns Hopkins University
1923-1925 Professor of History and Political Science, Hampden-Sydney College
1924, June 12 Married Betty Brown
1925-1936 Professor of History, University of Mississippi
1935-1938 Member, Board of Editors, Journal of Southern History
1936-1938 Associate professor of History, Duke University, Durham, N.C.
1938 Professor of History and Chairman of History Department, Duke University
1939 President, Southern Historical Association
1941-1944 Member, Executive Committee, North Carolina Literary and Historical Association
1947- Member, Board of Editors, South Atlantic Quarterly
1948 Litt.D., Washington and Lee University, and Princeton University (1953)
1949 President, North Carolina Literary and Historical Association
1950 M.A., University of Oxford, Oxford, England
1950-1951 Harold Vyvyan Harmsworth Professor of American History, University of Oxford
1952- Dean of Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, Duke University
1953 LL.D., Davidson College, Davidson, N.C.
1954 Died (buried in Chattanooga, Tenn.)
Sydnor's publications include Mississippi History, Slavery in Mississippi, A Gentleman of the Old Natchez Region: Benjamin L. C. Wailes, The Development of Southern Sectionalism, 1819-1848 (Volume V of The History of the South), and Gentlemen Freeholders: Political Practices in Washington's Virginia.
Sydnor held visiting professorships at Emory (1925-1926), Johns Hopkins (1929, 1934), Duke (1935-1936), Cornell (1941), University of North Carolina (1949), and Harvard (1952) Universities. He was a member of the Presbyterian Church, the Council Institute of Early American History and Culture, the Advisory Committee of the Office of the Chief of Military History for the U.S. Army, the American Historical Association, and the American Mississippi Valley Historical Association. He received awards from the Social Science Research Council (1940) and the Library of Congress (1945-1946).
Collection Overview
The Charles S. Sydnor Papers roughly span the period 1729-1978, the bulk dated 1923 to 1954. They include correspondence, research notes, writings, printed materials, and clippings, chiefly relating to Sydnor's teaching career at Duke University, as well as at Harvard and Queen's College, Oxford. The collection also includes information about his involvement with various historical associations and committees, including the American Historical Association, Southern Historical Association, North Carolina Literary and Historical Association, and the Advisory Committee of the Office of the Chief of Military History for the United States Army. There is background information pertaining to his various writings, including The Development of Southern Sectionalism (Volume V of the work A History of the South) (Baton Rouge, La., 1948), Gentleman Freeholders: Political Practices in Washington's Virginia (Chapel Hill, N.C., 1952), A Gentleman of the Old Natchez Region: Benjamin L. C. Wailes (Durham, N.C., 1938), Mississippi History (New York, N.Y., 1930), and Slavery in Mississippi (New York, N.Y., 1933). The papers contain notes and examinations for various history courses taught by Sydnor, student roll books, grade books, and papers. Additionally, there are a few notebooks and papers of Sydnor's while he was a student.
Materials relating to Sydnor's teaching career and participation in historical associations are found primarily in the Alphabetical Files Series and the Teaching Files Series. The information about Queen's College, University of Oxford, is located in the Alphabetical Files Series under Oxford. Information pertaining to his writings are found in the Writings and Speeches Series. Sydnor's own student notebooks and papers are found in the Miscellaneous Series. Topics highlighted include the Duke University Department of History during the late 1930s through the early 1950s, (Alphabetical Files Series); the writing and teaching of Southern history, particularly Mississippi history, (Writings and Speeches Series and Teaching Files Series); and the naturalist and planter, Benjamin L. C. Wailes (Writings and Speeches Series). A related collection in the Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library is the Benjamin L. C. Wailes Papers.
History teachers; Southern States -- History -- Historiography; Grading and marking (Students); Virginia -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865; Virginia -- Politics and government -- Colonial Period, ca. 1600-1775; Southern States -- History; Slavery -- United States -- Condition of slaves; Mississippi -- History; Slavery -- Mississippi; Slaves -- United States -- Social conditions; Duke University -- Faculty; North Carolina Literary and Historical Association; Harvard University. Dept. of History; Southern Historical Association; Duke University. Department of History; Queen's College (University of Oxford); United States. Dept. of the Army. Office of Military History; Wailes, Benjamin Leonard Covington, 1797-1862; Sydnor, Charles S. (Charles Sackett), 1898-1954.; American Historical Association
- Alphabetical Files Series, 1862-1954, undated (bulk 1925-1954).
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes correspondence, clippings, memoranda, and printed materials. Within this series are letters and documents which pertain to Sydnor's teaching posts at Duke University and elsewhere, his tenure as chairman of the History Department at Duke University, and his involvement in various professional societies. Also included are materials which document Sydnor's role as a member of the Advisory Committee of the Office of Chief of Military History for the United States Army. Arranged alphabetically by either correspondent or subject.
  - A, 1936-1954 (Box 1)
  - Abingdon-Cokesbury Press, 1952, Mar. 17-April 8 (Box 1)
  - American Historical Association:
    - American History Abroad--Oxford, 1951, May 17-July 13 (Box 1)
    - Programs, 1927-1951, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Andrews Raiders, 1906, Sept. 18-20 (Box 1)
  - B, 1927-1954, June, undated, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Bancroft Prize (John Krout), 1953, Aug.-1954, Mar. (Box 1)
  - Boyd, William K., 1938-1941, undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Brown family, 1929-1954 (Box 1)
  - C, 1926-1956, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Clippings: (Box 2)
    - 1927-1955 (Box 2)
    - Funeral, obituaries, Dr. Sydnor, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Columbia University, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - Commonwealth Fund, Sir Hector Hetheringtion, 1952, Oct. 1 (Box 2)
  - Condolence messages, Dr. Sydnor's death, 1954, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Converse College, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Cornell class roll, 1941 (Box 2)
  - D, 1926-1953, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Dancy Foundation Lectures Program, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Davidson College:
    - 1942-1953, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Honorary Degree (clippings), 1953 (Box 2)
  - Duke University Church, Committee Reports, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Duke University. Department of History:
    - Academic salary data, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Application, appointment, and report forms, 1947-1953, undated (Box 2)
    - Catalogue material for 1953-1954, submitted 1952, Nov. (Box 2)
    - Class census reports, history, 1952, Fall-1953, Fall, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Department conference and officers, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Departmental meetings:
      - 1952, Oct. 14 (Box 2)
      - 1953, Jan. 8 (Box 2)
    - Diplomatic history, faculty position for, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Edens, A. Hollis, 1949-1953 (Box 2)
    - Faculty, staff, course schedules, and office arrangements, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Graduate bulletin material, 1952, April (Box 2)
    - Graduate fellowships at Duke, publication of theses, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
    - Graduate programs of students not majoring with Sydnor, 1949-1953 (Box 2)
    - Graduate school, 1938-1953 (Box 2)
    - Gross, Paul, Letters to and from about policy in history graduate programs, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - History majors in Trinity College, 1953, Fall (Box 2)
    - Preparing Graduate Students for College Teaching, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
    - Research topics, thesis subjects, undated (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
  - Duke University Library, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
  - Duke University Library Council, 1939-1950 (Box 2)
  - Duke University Research Council
    - 1937-1954, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Carnegie Foundation, 1948-1950 (Box 2)
  - E, 1940-1951 (Box 3)
  - English-Speaking Union, 1950-1951 (Box 3)
  - F, 1933-1952 (Box 3)
  - Ferrell, Robert H., 1952 (Box 3)
  - Fleming, Walter Lynwood, lectures, programs, 1938-1949 (Box 3)
  - Fulbright program, 1950-1951, undated (Box 3)
  - G, 1923-1953, undated, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Gauhati University, Assam, India, 1951-1954, undated (Box 3)
  - Glasgow, University of, 1950-1951, undated (Box 3)
  - Green, Edward R. R., 1953 (Box 3)
  - H, 1936-1969, undated, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Hampden-Sydney College Alumni Fund, 1953, undated (Box 3)
  - Harvard University Summer School:
    - 1951-1952, undated (Box 3)
    - Housing, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Historical Society of North Carolina, 1945-1953, undated (Box 3)
  - Home: Oxford, Miss., 1928, undated (Box 3)
  - I, 1934-1952, undated (Box 3)
  - Income tax, 1918-1930 (Box 3)
  - J, 1926-1954 (Box 3)
  - Jameson, R. D., Library of Congress, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1922-1923 (Box 3)
  - Jordan, Charles E., 1949-1952, undated (Box 3)
  - K, 1925-1954, undated (Box 3)
  - Kearns Fellows Homecoming, 1953 (Box 3)
  - L, 1920-1954, undated, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Laprade, W. T., 1950-1953 (Box 3)
  - Library of Congress: Grant in Aid, 1945-1946 (Box 3)
  - M, 1925-1954, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Mc, 1919-1972, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Mississippi, 1935-1947 (Box 4)
  - Mississippi Conference Historical Society, 1935 (Box 4)
  - Mississippi Historical Society, Biloxi, Miss., 1953-1954 (Box 4)
  - Mississippi Valley Historical Society: Programs, 1937-1947 (Box 4)
  - Montgomery, Isaiah T., 1929-1937; undated (Box 4)
  - Morrison, Samuel Eliot, History as a Literary Art, undated (Box 4)
  - N, 1935-1953 (Box 4)
  - Nobel Peace Prize, 1953 (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Literary and Historical Association, 1948-1952 (Box 4)
  - O, 1929-1952 (Box 4)
  - Oxford, University of, and England: Miscellaneous, 1950-1951, undated (Box 4)
  - Oxford, University of: Addresses about, notes for, 1953-1954, undated (Box 4)
  - Oxford, University of: Beloff, Max, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
  - Oxford, University of: Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
  - Oxford, University of, Queen's College:
    - 1950-1953, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Class rolls and notes, undated (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Registrar, provost, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1951 (Box 4)
  - P, 1930-1953, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1939-1940, undated (Box 4)
  - Pogue, Forrest C., 1951-1952 (Box 4)
  - Presbyterian Church, 1922-1954 (Box 4)
  - Presbyterian Church in the United States: Board of Education, 1946-1952 (Box 5)
  - Presbyterian Church, First (Durham, N.C.), 1948-1954, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Presbyterian Church Youth Literature, 1943-1946, undated (Box 5)
  - Princeton Conference of Historians, 1953, Oct. 30-31 (Box 5)
  - Princeton University: Honorary degree, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Q, 1940-1952 (Box 5)
  - R, 1930-1959, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - S, 1931-1956, 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Sabbatical:
    - 1941-1953, undated, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Fulbright grant, 1949-1950, undated (Box 5)
    - Huntington Library, 1949, undated (Box 5)
  - Salzburg Seminar in American Studies, 1950-1952, undated (Box 5)
  - Scotland, 1951, undated (Box 5)
  - Simon, F. E., A Scientist Looks at America, 1950-1951 (Box 5)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1939-1953, undated (Box 5)
  - Southern Historical Association: 1934-1952, undated, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Southern Historical Association: Programs, 1934-1951 (Box 6)
  - Southwestern Social Science Association: Programs, 1932 (Box 6)
  - Sydnor family genealogy, 1862-1952 (Box 6)
  - T, 1934-1953 (Box 6)
  - Theses written under the direction of Charles S. Sydnor: List of early theses written at Duke, 1937-1953, undated (Box 6)
  - Trinity College Historical Society:
    - 1952-1954 (Box 6)
    - Publications, 1950-1953 (Box 6)
  - U, 1932-1948 (Box 6)
  - United Educators, 1934-1936 (Box 6)
  - United States Army addresses and notes, 1944, undated (Box 6)
  - United States Army History, 1953, Feb.-Aug. (Box 6)
  - United States Department of Education, 1952-1953 (Box 6)
  - United States. Department of the Army. Office of Military History, 1949-1953, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - University of Chattanooga, Phi Beta Kappa, 1935, Dec. (Box 6)
  - University of Michigan, 1940 (Box 6)
  - University of Mississippi, 1927-1954, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Summer School, 1949 (Box 6)
  - V, 1926-1952 (Box 6)
  - W, 1925-1954, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Washington and Lee University, 1947-1949 (Box 6)
  - Williams, William A., 1952 (Box 6)
  - Williamsburg:
    - Institute of Early American History and Culture, 1950-1953, 4 folders (Box 6)
    - The Candidates, 1949 (Box 6)
  - World Book Encyclopedia, 1941-1947 (Box 6)
  - X-Z, 1934-1958 (Box 6)
- Writings and Speeches Series, 1729-1954 (bulk 1923-1954).
  Includes research materials and notes, as well as drafts and off-prints, which document the development of Sydnor's published works and addresses. Included are notes and drafts for Gentleman Freeholders: Political Practices in Washington's Virginia, and The Development of Southern Sectionalism, 1819-1849. A handwritten duplicate of a document, signed by James Madison on April 18, 1810, certifying the appointment of Levin Wailes as the Register for the Land Office of the United States for the western part of the Orleans Territory is among the oversize materials for this series (See OC:II:7). Included are research materials from the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. The two major categories are Writings and Background Materials, each arranged alphabetically. At the end are Miscellaneous Materials. The background materials include Sydnor's research notes, but it has not been determined for which particular writing they were created.
  - Writings
    - Aristocracy and Politics in Revolutionary Virginia, American Historical Association/Southern Historical Association, 1948 (Box 6)
    - Article mailing lists, undated (Box 6)
    - The Beginning of Printing in Mississippi, 1934-1935, undated (Box 6)
    - The Biography of a Slave, 1826-1937 (Box 6)
    - Blazer Lecture, University of Kentucky, 1951 (Box 6)
    - B.L.C. Wailes, Scientist and Historian, undated (Box 6)
    - The Christian as an Interpreter of History, ca. 1953 (Box 6)
    - A Description of Seargeant S. Prentiss in 1838, 1944-1945 (Box 6)
    - The Development of Southern Sectionalism, 1819-1848: (Box 7)
      - Stylesheet and outlines, undated (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1918-1937, undated, 7 folders (Box 7)
      - Usage notes, contents, preface, 1946, undated (Box 7)
      - Chapter I, The Awakened South (Box 7)
      - Chapter II, Location of Political Power (Box 7)
      - Chapter III, Enlightenment of Public Opinion (Box 7)
      - Chapter IV, Toward a More Perfect Society (Box 7)
      - Chapter V, Crises in Business and Politics (Box 7)
      - Chapter VI, From Economic Nationalism to Political Sectionalism (Box 7)
      - Chapter VII, End of the Virginia Dynasty (Box 7)
      - Chapter VIII, The Lower South Adopts States' Rights (Box 7)
      - Chapter IX, Bold Acts and Bolder Thoughts (Box 7)
      - Chapter X, Prologue to the End of Slavery (Box 7)
      - Chapter XI, Vicissitudes of an Agricultural Economy (Box 7)
      - Chapter XII, Movement Toward Political Democracy (Box 7)
      - Chapter XIII, Religion, Education, Literature (Box 7)
      - Chapter XIV, Political Weakness and Social Perfection (Box 7)
      - Preface, chapters I-XIII, revised, 14 folders (Box 7)
      - Chapter XIV, Party Allegiance for Sectional Patriotism, rev. (Box 7)
      - Chapter XV, The Affirmation of Southern Perfection, rev. (Box 7)
      - Fragment of a manuscript, undated (Box 7)
      - Illustrations, undated, 3 folders (Box 7)
      - Bibliography, undated (Box 7)
      - Legends and bibliography to accompany maps of presidential elections of 1824, 1828, 1832, undated (Box 7)
      - Notes concerning maps of presidential elections, undated (Box 7)
      - Critical bibliography, undated (Box 7)
      - Index, undated (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous, 1947, undated (Box 7)
      - Correspondence: Louisiana State University Press, 1939-1968 (Box 7)
    - The Development of Southern Sectionalism, 1819-1848: (Box 8)
      - Reviews, clippings, 1940-1951, undated, 2 folders (Box 8)
      - Mayflower Cup Award, 1948-1949 (Box 8)
    - Diary of a Journey in Arkansas in 1856, Mississippi Valley Historical Review, 1935, Dec. (Box 8)
    - Dictionary of American Biography (DAB):
      - Correspondence, 1927-1934 (Box 8)
      - Featherston, W. S., 1928 (Box 8)
      - Foote, Henry S., undated (Box 8)
      - George, James Z., 1930 (Box 8)
      - Gordon, James, 1930 (Box 8)
      - Leflore, Greenwood, 1931 (Box 8)
      - Martin, William T., 1933 (Box 8)
      - McLautin, A. J., undated (Box 8)
      - McRae, J. J., undated (Box 8)
      - Mayes, Edward, undated (Box 8)
      - Money, H. D., undated (Box 8)
      - Orr, J. A., 1930-1934 (Box 8)
      - Poindexter, George, 1931 (Box 8)
      - Prentiss, S. S., 1931 (Box 8)
      - Sharkey, W. L., 1931-1935 (Box 8)
      - Singleton, O. R., 1932 (Box 8)
      - Smith, James Argyle, 1932 (Box 8)
      - Stewart, Alexander Peter, 1932 (Box 8)
      - Stockdale, Thomas R., 1932 (Box 8)
      - Stone, John Marshall, undated (Box 8)
      - Thompson, Jacob, 1932-1934 (Box 8)
      - Turner, Edward, 1933-1936 (Box 8)
      - Vardaman, James K., 1933 (Box 8)
      - Wailes, B. L. C., 1933-1936 (Box 8)
      - Walthall, E. C., 1933 (Box 8)
      - Williams, John Sharp, 1934-1935 (Box 8)
      - Yerger, William, 1934 (Box 8)
    - Dissertation notes, 1923?, 4 folders (Box 8)
    - Essays on Law and Conscience in American History, outline and notes, 1949, undated (Box 8)
    - Fleming lectures, Louisiana State University:
      - Carbons, undated (Box 8)
      - Correspondence, programs, 1952-1954 (Box 8)
      - Drafts and notes, 1954, undated (Box 8)
    - The Free Negro in Mississippi Before the Civil War, 1927-1935 (Box 8)
    - Free negroes: Background material 1705-1860, undated, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Free negroes: (Box 9)
      - Notes relating to, 1789-1941, undated, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Transcribed letters and documents from the Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1788-1938 (Box 9)
    - Gentleman Freeholders:
      - Abbot notes, used in Ch. VI, 1761-1775, undated (Box 9)
      - Abbot's notes of House of Burgesses Committees, 1761-1775, undated (Box 9)
      - Background information, 1947-1951, undated, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Charles City and Northumberland County, Wicomico and South Farhan Notes, 1703-1876, undated (Box 9)
      - A Collection of Plays and Poems by the late Colonel Robert Munford, 1798, undated (Box 9)
      - Contested Elections:
        - House of Burgesses Journals, undated (Box 9)
        - Virginia, 1948-1950, undated (Box 9)
      - The County Court/Albermarle, Essex, undated (Box 9)
      - Dissenters, research and correspondence relating to, 1948-1950 (Box 9)
      - Justice of the Peace: Economic and social status, undated (Box 9)
      - Madison, James, 1923, undated (Box 9)
      - Madison, James, Papers: Library of Congress, undated (Box 9)
      - Percentages of Virginia Legislators Who Were Justices of the Peace, 1776-1861, undated (Box 9)
      - Potential film based on book, 1952-1953, undated (Box 9)
      - Political ladder in Washington's Virginia, 1942-1952, undated (Box 9)
      - Reviews, 1952-1953 (Box 9)
      - Tabulations of Virginia elections (1788), 1946 (Box 9)
      - Tucker-Coleman Papers, Colonial Williamsburg, undated (Box 9)
      - Virginia demographic information, 1790-1948 (Box 9)
      - Virginia elections, 1740s-1840s polls; F. Taylor's diary, undated (Box 9)
      - Virginia political leadership (1775-1800):
        - Sketches, 1948, undated (Box 9)
        - Rise to power of political leaders, undated (Box 9)
      - Preface and front pages, undated (Box 9)
      - Chapters I-IX (9 folders), undated (Box 9)
      - Bibliographical note, undated (Box 9)
      - Appendix I-II (2 folders), undated (Box 9)
      - Index, undated (Box 9)
      - Carbon of last copy lacking Ch. VI, undated (Box 9)
      - Index to, undated (Box 9)
      - Fragment of a manuscript, undated (Box 9)
    - Gentleman Freeholders: (Box 10)
      - Correspondence, 1946-1956, undated (Box 10)
    - A Gentleman of the Old Natchez Region: Benjamin L. C. Wailes:
      - Announcements and reviews, 1938-1939, undated (Box 10)
      - Maps, photographs, and tables, 1922-1937, undated (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 10)
      - Notes, undated, 4 folders (Box 10)
      - Publication documents, 1937, undated (Box 10)
      - Revision notes used, 1891-1936, undated (Box 10)
    - Historical Activities in Mississippi in the Nineteenth Century, 1937 (Box 10)
    - Historical Comments on American Democracy, Mississippi Historical Society, 1954, undated (Box 10)
    - Intellectual Activities in the Old Natchez District, American Historical Association, 1936 (Box 10)
    - Lee, Guy A., The Historian and the Federal Government, American Historical Association, 1949-1950, n.d (Box 10)
    - Letter from Alexander M. Clayton Relative to Cuban Affairs, 1929 (Box 10)
    - Letters from Franklin L. Riley to Herbert B. Adams (1894-1901), 1935-1940 (Box 10)
    - Life Span of Mississippi Slaves, 1926-1930 (Box 10)
    - Mississippi History:
      - Correspondence and corrections, 1938-1940 (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1925-1927? (Box 10)
      - Pictures, 1863- 1930, undated, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - The Old South as a Laboratory for Cultural Analysis, University of Michigan, 1940 (Box 10)
    - The Old South to the New, undated (Box 10)
    - The One Party Period of American History, 1942-1946 (Box 10)
    - Phi Beta Kappa address, University of South Carolina, 1949-1950 (Box 10)
    - Political Leadership in Eighteenth-Century Virginia, published lecture, 1950-1951 (Box 10)
    - Possibilities of a Historic Highway through Mississippi, University of Mississippi, undated (Box 10)
    - A Possible Source of Calhoun's plan of Nullification, Mississippi Valley Historical Association, undated (Box 10)
    - Press Censorship in England, 1534-1603, (dissertation), 1923 (Box 10)
    - Pursuing Fugitive Slaves, 1929-1935 (Box 10)